So, welcome...
building and thank you for stay until the last this last day of butte.
And, the today we have a really fun session for
you this is a deploying complex open-source work workloads on
manager and because this is open-source session
...did the session in open-source way and you can see...have
four speakers on the stage and main of us have a math until yesterday
...two guys are just introducing themselves on the stage was
a really interesting so we have a common go
...go for us we want to introduce open-source on adder
we want to explain to you how we bring open-source workloads on...and how we make them
...thrive on the address platform and the...separate our work into small
pieces essentially each of us will come from different angles we bring our own
experiments and we introduce what we've done with our customers and ponders
...the hope to show some of them to you todaywe haveI
think six demos and...model...so...get started but before we
...we go and there's just a...the introduce introduction so I'm
...technically evangelist for microsoft and google?
It microsoft tech in the technical vandalism group focused on the opensource
large big data projects.
...I'm a program manager...as a compute team and I work on which
...machines and I've been working on that for the last two years
breiman's a work for microsoft open technologies and I specialize in working with a
open-source on as your devices technical evangelist is my title and
...specific...working lately with java and are partnerships with ibm and oracle...few others?
Right that's got started.
Our agenda today is actually really easy we have three parts
...first one is to...how microsoft laughs open-source them to
explain why you want to use open-source...then we'll go through some of
some of scenarios but open-source is a such large topic
...what wave touch of what...be covering here is only
...very small set of the open-source community so you some of the framework
of technologies we don't cover here don't
feel bad because we'll come we know that much.
To explain how adrg laugh open-source I think the best way to prove this is to
...review
what's happened in the past year a model as in the past twelve-month.
And, in case you don't know about twenty percent of virtual machines on adder
...linux so address not about the nad only it's not
about windows-only is...linux will running other than
...languages as a method matter-of-fact we just announced
hd inside does our service now
...linux as well and you feel following microsoft
...open sourcing is core technology essentially the done that
...done a framework is going open-source now you have the of course
...on open-source and are mono project is taking the course
...code back to the moon as well?
Askjan that is broken from the and you don't have to host ascii
than I website...anymore we adopted this open standard which allows us to break
the web application from the web server which means you can wholesale sp done ad no-cost
fromprocess you can wholesale sq
...the concert vacation you want and
...mono and...in the future you can run sp than
...linux unix darker containment that's all possible actually...the
some post today out there that we can run sp done website on the...container.
the open-source is also changing how microsoft is delivering our own services
...instead of trying to build everything from ground-up
we're looking all the market will look at the most popular
and most proven open-source technologies and then we put represent...we putwe
...value-added services we manage the resources for you we gave you the service level
agreement...puts like monitoring the...appalled all those value-added
services but underneath the open-source technologies one good example is the adder...is
cash which use read this engine underneath another example is
...research which uses the elastic search behind-the-scenes.
And, now...is taking over the industry
...has this deep integration with stocker is
...not just talking about running adopter engine on the virtual machine I mean everybody can do
it of for microsoft we have a really deep
...if you see the keynote from
...state announced the windows containers and the way we
did the windows container was really a unique
...windows container integrated with stocker at a very low-level at
...very low api level which means all the existent
tagger tools and oper api seo familiar with you can use the same tool to
manage both linux and windows containers actually will show a brief them right after this.
And, of course as part of the openness microsoft has been
working with all kinds of summarization bob...actually we're working with over
hundred-fifty standardization bodies and over four hundred workshops around the world
to establish a adopt an advocate for...and
...examples you will see is the m q piece appalled and opie see support
the union...scenarios and last but not least the
success of a open-source is based on the strong community so that's why
...has this template which will
...moment and...we have things
...marketplace and revamp people which contains hundreds
...thousands of templates and how...bootstrap your workload on
advert and get going really quickly and...we'll talk about...people with...well?
So, this really gave us a very.
...and reach open-source community on
adrg you'll laugh some framework was
...tools chances are you'll find...dieter.
And, in terms of development you can use your own
familiar tools languages databases and develop on your similar
devices and integration with a lot of open-source the solutions.
I think...are a...you the best way...we have really made sure that
...is a very open platform it's not just about the nad
...windows may have the most...of structure we want to
...in this heterogeneous word when it comes to the public...
So, with that.
Like I said we have...them with a want to both rather
...as possible so I will show the for the first set of demo...tool to demos
...the windows container on darker you know, I know there was some demos
...keynote by this one will be different so in this one we're going to the apply a...
propped server...java based on the windows container and we'll see how that works
...scenario I'm going to show is to...how to apply a mango db across the
region entry across content and replica using measure and this is
...of our a...a e-commerce...and
the first question ...ask when the...adrg was if we can get
...db to work with a process regionreplicas so...jumped into the demos.
the first one we're going to show is oper.
This is are the...for windows
you can this is just regular windows application you can operate on top
of continuous remotely so this is a and creating a new
of windows container...I have is the windows can
...image this and this is an like sling
...windows contains all the windows...
system libraries and now I'm actually in the contain and this is not on my local
machine anymore this is the windows container running on my machine
certain to the dothere are...
In full.
...a commiserate...a fully functional
windows but now I want to do something really terrible to this box I won't say
...eg deletes...
Software.
Some deleting a whole chunk of registers, you know, this will be really,
really bad to the windows box but I'm going to do this anyway.
...will...well because we've taken all the stuff...now
basically my boxes broken...do something basic like help.
Cannot only do this anymore it's.
Useful years broken how barges self locate broken as
well so basically there's nothing much I can do with this box but I can exit and just nothing happened
this continuous gong when...to the next time I ever get a fresh container everything...works.
...less interesting this to some more interesting stuff.
...I have the container named the main...
...server.
Smpte.
So, this is the image I built a...familiar with stocker I need to do is to define
...define the commands and file see wanting
...this image and you build it then you can run so now I'm
this microsoft a container if it...if you can fake...can get
...ip addresses by us that would use in a
command-line I will use remote desktop can I put this guy and see...who was on it.
As it turned thirty five...that one hundred eighty scaling.
Password.
So, now I'm remote desktop...my container this just feel like a like a windows
...let's see if I go to...make this function who bigger.
You can see I have some file
preloaded on this I have the java runtime already installed you might profile and
...this microbe the server the one that...the for portion I'm
...to lunch but before I do thatI want to show you some interactions you can
do between the...host and...container itself so I'm going to the
host machine that is hosting the container this is a host.
And, if a open...
Manager.
You can actually on here I have a container
...volume here that's actually mapped to
my container see the system drive.
But, here on the host...assign a different drive...intuit.
Neck interest uses a regular drive...the.
...can say.
...hello.
Ok,...file and what
I have also under my host of computer?
I have a different service server contribution...they want to use this is the
server data properties and just going to copy this file.
And, now if I go back to my container have the keep track
...and...and back to my
container first let's look for that the file.
You can see the hello that fi type...hello the...three.
This cat.
Noise tip
...switch between linux and windows commence but anyway so I
have this configuration for file ...the and...to launch men craft server.
Handcraft...
As I said this is a java application it depends on runtime but we can told you that
...installed by the by that are profile.
This will take a while now I have...the server.
And, was...address...guy I forgot now this blanche amend craft
...works.
So, this...client.
...to find the ip address.
However, use multiplayer.
And, into...to a direct...this of different ip this...of course.
This...turn...the one hundred eighty seven.
And, here I'm running microsoft in a windows container
...local box and just to show I can actually
...this I'm going to back to my...server.
I'm going to change myself an administrator.
Go-slow today oop.
Actually I have a...story to tell about this unfortunate use...
The high pick person
...basically...I was trying to...bankrupt
him has some problem with my credit card so I asked my sister
...to pay the bill for me and just
...it doesn't matter how old you are...older sister will still
...all kinds of pranks on you so she name me the pig person and unfortunately
...this name cannot be changed so, I'm the paid person ever since?
But,...okay and the mind.
So, now I promoting myself as an administrator if I do this.
Can do some advanced roughneck whether mccann...
Now it's raining so this is a real functional
...crowd server on the windows container so that's the first...
I think that's...a good demo for friday right.
Ok, now let's talk about...or time already
okay now let's talk about most serious stuff this huge jump from microsoft
...db ok so as I said...
room we spoke to this customer the first...because they're a huge among db user
the first question they ask is that can you run the cross continent replicas
...on...adrg...we said sure...
to it so this is architecture we came upbasically we set up to virtual networks
...us when in western europe and they are connected through a service
...virtual network to which network connection we have this
...that you can bridge the different version networks
...if you didn't notice we just announced the new cheer of this
getaway that provides a much more throughput than before and you can
...is expression...where.
You can use a dedicated the connection as well so the throughput is not
a problem the performance was great data problems task the latency
select a hundred milliseconds or something like that so in this setting way we determine
are us west will be the primary site we have a...server and the second
...in this by the we'll use the west europe as a backup so the backup is a
members arrays saddam a secondary and the parity of it is
set to zero so that it is an never elective as the primary
the reason we do this is that because all the workloads is actually close to the us west we
...a minimum latency but way bonded this
...over tool west europe you've something really bad happened.
So, to do this what we did...we use a couple things in combination
...the advocate online tools we use adrg extensions and
...scripts of course you in this
...did everything kind of manually we...all the scripts and drive all the
deployment process...the hash...in a moment if you introduce the advertise
...which is a much declarative way for your to capture
...structure so this particular...what we did is that we read
a puddle scripts first we have a muster script that-you rhino client?
...drive all the provisioning process and we have among machines
...this machine will be executed on all member service
we upload this script into a ...storage now what the...scribble do it will create
the virtual network...provision of virtual machines the on virtual machines
...will enable custom script extension this...the one of the virtual machine extensions
with support...just in case you don't know the virtual machine extension is a small
program that you can install unger new or existing virtual machines that
...virtual machine different ways for instance you...under virus environment
...want chef or poppy integration or in this case if you run a
...script you can use the different extensions and they will take care the business
for you so in this case we're setting up the primaries and
second race and they all have possum squared extensions enabled and what's this
machines are launched they will go to the
...storage account download the script and...locally so this
...db and configure some...files and drawing...into the replica site.
So, for this I'm going to...
Give you another demo.
I'm going to jump on a want-to books.
So, first I'm going to show you the muster...
Have the create a different version because we need to mask the customer name by use some name leaked
...I apologize...so,
again, this script actually we're creating of five machine clusters so we're create a
...invest us and to europe?
So, we...enabling endpoints that urinate this is...what-you.
Want-to do for ...deployment you want to keep your
...database private behind the virtual network buffer the demonstration
...purpose we open up the in point so we can access those machines from
public and then here's the complex partly looks a little scary but essentially with
...it does is specified...which storage account and the rich
...a can...you need to download that script.
Then...specify whether...to be
executed on the machine in this case I'm just calling the on machine script.
So, let me create...
And,...machine script me show you this...
You can see the once is honest on the machine is just to the regular shell script stuff
download...some host names and just start a new cluster.
And, that's the results
...me connect to one of this I think with the muster.
...than it.
...see now I'm connected...the to the primary you
...you users.
Find...three users here.
And, if I open another...script.
I'm going to connect to...secondary of.
...right I'm going to connect a second
...in western europe let's say.
The cfive...time.
You can see I'm on the secondary.
I would do queries from the myspace.
And, if I am by...primary.
You can see the status them my replica site.
The first one the mango one
that's the primary university us and we have to
...and you can see the ping time between them is
...minimum is millisecond and the other two the
...for an...five there you invest a europe the
...is...bigger the big deal so now let me
...for the...and then you...the new...user.
First thing we have...now.
James sorry.
Ok, and, I'll give you a score like two hundred.
The tv users insert
this user so I'm guessing this through the primary and the first switch to secondary.
You can see...eradicated so this is across content...the replica almost
linear time...we set up you need to...squares so
...this part of demo so the next topic like I mentioned I hope I
approved some points that we really lob open-source we're making our efforts to
embrace though open-sourcecommunity but useful resource has is
...on...some of open-source projects
are not as stable is some kind is just a one person doing open-source project
...he-he-he...interests so there are
some other things if you have this one for technology you still need to manage all the resources that the
support...framework for instance you...longer-run maybe storm you
need to provision all the virtual machines and organism together so this is a
why address...is assertion important technology it allows you to
...the entire instructor ice-cold this includes not only are first part
...services but other also the open-source services and to speak to that I
will in
by the expert mahesh...tell you about this part cool thanks actually right.
We are about half the half the time so I'm just going to kind of run through.
All right I think the of so I'm hash what I'm going to talk about
is what we announced and buildthis time
...the announced support for the
template in capability for compute network and storage resources what this means is now you
can go architect whatever highly showed as five ten different
scripps in a single script and just deployed in a cyclic so, we actually have
mono db high availability cluster template available already on as a dot com
so you should be able to go find it and in a single...you should be able to go deploy among db
high available cluster without having to do a lot of the work we just
...so that's the our of what...announcing with the build announcement now
before I go to...I want to just kinda introduce ...talk a little bit...as your some of the?
Key parts about what we did with as you're right we
wanted to make sure thathad a few key aspects about being a truly scalable
...we focus a lot of hyper scale you know, if you are going to be around you know,
for the next session I'm going to talk and showcase and I think how she's going to probably do a demo...
scalability as well we've truly gone hyper scale...of services and measure and I think we have an
introduces...another services that talks about the scalability in the cloudwe truly enterprise
good grade and I think we talked a lot about the certifications we have a lot of the compliance
...to make sure that any apps that, you know, that customers need a can be mapped with the
enterprise great capability that we havewe also hybrid when I say hybrid a
...multiple bridges a hybrid across the sample that we talked about where you can
connect multiple...is hybrid...also work a lot on making
hybrid connectivity possible between on premises and...as well so when I say hybrid you can actually connect your
on...and...to measure and with this
as a template capability that we just announced we also made an announcement about how the template file
that you guys deployed are architected can actually work with on from this to
so a single...file that you actually go model to deploy...db will not just work on
manager going forward you can take the same...file go deployed against on
...and linemen which is managed badger...so...
The single unify...is what you're getting...no more...the business of just hey do something what
...go to something else from premises
...just write a bunch of scripts to connect them it's all about just a single file that allows you to
manage and app between on premises an actor so that's...that we made all right and,
I think just being an enterprise great cloud there's a lot of you know,
things that we focus onmaking sure an infrastructure layer we have...or...security then
that at a vm level how we ensure security we make sure that there is no we protect your...against
...attacks avi make sure that we provide the application-level
security controls likeness application-level security controls thinking about you know,
integration with the, you know, giving you extensions that allows you to install and
...ibm's giving you the platform capabilities for protecting your endpoints on the
cloud giving,
you know, the integration with casual keyboard to make sure that you get first-class capability
where you can store your keys and as a keywords but then you can certificates accusing...deployed
is lms you can fetch them on-the-fly so we provide first-class security control and capabilities
...integration of virtual machines and adjective...so this is truly an enterprise grade cloud with,
you know,...security being provided every layer from starting from
physical to infrastructure layer down to the platform layer of the networking level and
then inside the vm as well so inside the...you get like on-demand were insecurity extensions and integration
...okay so the next five minutes I'm going to talk briefly about what we
announced so, I need to introduce a couple of concepts you guys the first concept that I'm going to
introduces the concept of resource groups resource group is think of them
as a container the software container which...your application together it could be
an application...be a set of resources that have identical lifecycle
...the case of the example that...pointed out from under db you could think of place your entire
...the application...an entire research group the reason why we place the
resource group together is it gives you the controls to manage that entity as a whole
a good example is let's say you're doing some development and testing and you're like hey I'm spending...three node...I
wanted to do some profess and I'm done so...if you want to go clean that environment up you have to go
libm one...the...the...no more you can actually just delete the
...group forget about this and then actually have an entire control of resource group
...entity to manage your application the other aspect about resource groups
...we also have the support for tagging tagging is very powerful and,
you tag resource it's not just for querying and searching for like a applicant among...
db what it does these tags propagate through the system and actually show up in your bill at the end of
the month so imagine a case where...sharing a subscription multiple
users can actually have each user tag their own entities...the month can actually build
the...file...comes out of the end of the...can actually pivot chart and look at...from on the db how...I
for spend from adapt here how much of my engineering departments...how much...my it...can actually go
do all of the configuration by using this tagging capability and the reason why resource
...helps is imagine a case where you're building a scalable front-end...have two hundred
...you it's impossible to go manage and, you know, confident every individual bm so the resource
group as a container that you can go tag that and say this tag is just for the web here and
...propagates and all the...lms addendum on you can actually get the clogs, you know, completely
meshed and the seen as a single entity...very helpful from that the
third thing around that is a rule-based access control so rule-based access control is you know,
anytime you provision subscription measure you get an active directory tenant as part
of it so you can go ad users are groups as part of active directory tenant say let's say you
have to users one...admin or database admin the other...a network admin
...is an overall admin so you can actually have different resource groups caddy the database
another resource could that carries the networking configuration you can have the
network admin only be the person responsible for coddling or changing the network properties and
sql admin or the database admin doesn't...change that so...only access
...access...get can completely slice and dice and provide the right amount of security
...across the different research group...application appropriately?
And, resource group spans multiple regions so in this case of among db sample you could
have resource groupwhere you can actually have a three-m sitting invest us and...
sitting invest europe but you manage the whole entity as an application that you just look at it from a single research
group you can do that okay templates so I think I'm not sure if we do a
template later but if you are around do stick around...next session will go deep dive into templates
but high-level templates are nothing but think of them as a as a model fly
defines the configuration of your deployment including the infrastructure and it also contains
the configuration of the apps that-you want-to configure inside the
via it's not just okay I need five...that's not you can actually say I have to
run script warm to go configure...first and then I have to run script to actually joined the
...or something like that so you can actually have the entire apps defined in a single complex
...or multiple template files actually link them together the key part about the template
...so when you actually say let's say you deployed on
...zero with...iams and you come back later and say I want to add
...to it you can use the same template file just change some properties and
...deployed again we will detect...only the first oem
...up and running so we spent the next ibm's so we have that our
...simplifies orchestration,
orchestration is not...just at the infrastructure layer orchestration can be done for even for the
...you can actually have to...and say script to on...should not run
...script...done so you're not just orchestrating saying wait for of infrastructure to be spun up
also defining dependencies between...that are running inside the box you have the our of
going deploying...our app without having to worry about you
re doing the work again and again simplifies roll back a little bit because if you are doing some devon task your
...setting the environment you don't have to worry about overrated get stuck you can just like go delete that
...scope use the template again start a new...it gives you the flexibility of devon
...in a very simple fashion and,
it supports cross resources configuration support so
...applications that involve hey, you know, I want to go use service bus...actually put use
...my front-end but I want to confident...the...so for applications around where you want to
...across resources on measure this template...carry...it's not just tied
to compute network and storage is for all of the resource types that exists on manager that undergraduate
thesis manager...can package them into a single file and deployed as an application
we view the as...temple files a source files that are checked and it's not stored on the cloud it's something that you can
...your source control can be...get we've announced a lot of
template support on get as well so you should go take a look at them and,
the parameterization part of the templates makes it very reputable?
Here's a quick screen shot of the template location but,
the key the key points here are really around you know,
complexity made simple you don't have to worry about handling ten different files you can just have a single file the
deployment app we are blending theyou know,
thinking about apps more than just infrastructure
you can actually blend your eyes and pass applications together and get your aptitude desire we've
focused a lot of scaleability so the ability to spin up the m on measures really, really fast so it's
going to be scalable deployments...provided language capabilities in the template where you can easily
scale-up and down so you can actually say hey I want to...sign up seven node cassandra cluster, for example,
and, we will detect and just be able to...up seven nodes and, then the integration
...access control on tags makes it very powerful for you to go build and app and actually maintain and
manager going forward but...I'm going to...handed back to...demo.
I do apologize I use too much time at the beginning so I think we'll
skip the next demo this...demo essentially this is a repeat of micros
...demo on the first so I think you can just which video
there that's...in the summer scenarios we have three...some of scenarios I hope we can still
cover those magically somehow so the first one...the above the...nance
dec for that I will you might brian to talk about...thanks so,
there's a couple things I want to show you today actually actually was going to jump into the demo I think because we
a lot of time to go through slides.
Or on okay so what I want to show you today so the easiest thing to show you a
...stack is wordpress and, I've got a fairly complicated configuration
that I put together I've actually here's, here's the wordpress site this is
a virtual machine on clap dot net and,
basically this is a template...template you can go in and ask a question
input answer and things like that then we have an
as your website the exact same thing if I put a new
post in here it's going to update on both sites on the as a website and on the virtual
machinebecause what I've done is actually point...of them at a sequel
...my sequel database so, behind-the-scenes?
...just skip over that.
Where's that diagram.
...skip through all these.
I guess we missed the diagram okay ogg version control issues.
That's okay I can cover that so basically what I've got
here what you're looking at...put back in five then.
...save time...and work.
So, basically what you've got here when I did this is I split out the my
sequel database into a separate vm and I
eight-point the vm running wordpress and the app the
web app running wordpress
...that my sequel database on the separate vm now how you actually said that
up there's a couple ways to do it in the way I did it is.
Basically when you go to wordpress.
All use where matrix today.
You can go and you get the sh.
And, you just go in and actually edit these...edit the live site
...that graphic...that graphic I don't usually write code but when I do
...in production have you seen that thing is pretty good let me show you that actually.
I should have this ready.
Whoops note that one.
...very good one but I don't always...my code when I do
...in productions so.
Like that will graphic anyway, so, we can go into web matrix.
We can actually change the file which is in
...configure sample file here and show you
and that sample file basically you just edit these settings
...the right database...password username things like that so it's pretty simple
...how do I actually get the web app going there's a couple ways to do that
...go through the gallery here you just say new.
The marketplace web app from gallery.
And, we've got wordpress and a couple other things as well.
Down here there's a regular wordpress in the japanese...fire wordpress.
And, you put in some parameters here...creates that the way I set
up the vm was through vm...how many people have heard of vm...
A couple of a good so we're something...cover today the and depot is a repository.
Virtual machines.
And, inside that repository virtual machine is about seven hundred of them they're all
...all free and they're all open-source so the way I did this
actually is I chose this actual item here you go through here
...vm depot...microsoft open tech dot com as url in click on deployment script make
...happy you pick a region brazil
south this gives you...I how many people are familiar with the...I the command-line
interface for measure ok so there's a command-line interface for as you can download is node
based and you can actually use this script cut-and-paste
...some parameters in...specific to your subscription and the server you want to...and
things like that and it will actually deploy that out to...a full wordpress stack with it's got
...patchy is got my sql it's got wordpress
...php all configured together and ready to run it only takes a few minutes
things about five minutes to fired up and you can actually run that if you don't even want to learn how
use description...I you can go into the new portal.
And, hopefully we haven't timed out here if I go to the marketplace good.
So, I can choose one of these wordpress tampa's these are the actual gallery templates everything's kind of mixed together
new portal but you see down here there's a couple of different wordpress
virtual machines if I click on virtual machines.
Includes all the wordpress images that I just showed you on.
On vm...and with these
you can literally just click on one of them let's do a wordpress four-two.
Where's that one.
Something even more exotic here.
Wordpress on engine x with per...perricone of my sequels one of the
options you can get from there you say create and it gives you a bunch
of settings you can set up a resource group...set up all kinds of information there
about the...prove configure endpoints things like that when you click on create is actually
going to go ahead and create that vm for-you as well so it's even easier you don't even need to learn the
ci...the scripts or anything like that through the new poorly
you can do it that way so as I show you what I did after that is I went in and I went through
a matrix to change the image to point at a.
A database that I createdand, actually how did I
create the database infrastructure I didn't actually created from scratch.
I...another vm depot image is just a...stack image.
The...stack image gives you something that's kind of handy for.
It actually gives you.
A bunch of.
Features that you can use like php my bb and a few other
things for managing a...stack that I only used my
...part of it I copied using my sequel dump which is a tool for my
sequel I took that and copy the actual database from my wordpress instance
on the vm to the lap stack instance
use and endpoint everything to it to point from the vm
that runs wordpress the vienna runs my
...I just use wins cp you just go in there instead of
...you can go through the command-line you can do all kinds of things but I just go through when cp and you go into
...configured that php here
...to open it up because it has all the parameters and passwords and things and,
it just basically edit here and...again once again I didn't production which probably in the
way to do it if you're using a real...but that was the easiest way to do it for here.
So, that in a nutshell is the wordpress part of the demo I want to show you.
All of the stuff that we have here
...I mentioned I used all the.
Vm depot images all linux running a
...wordpress my sequel and then
I scaled out the image from.
I actually use the web app which is
little more scaleable there's two things you can do for scaling the
...m as wellhere knows there's wean traffic manager and load balance or couple
people okay so basically we have to features for scaling ibm's we
have traffic manager and we have load balance or traffic manager works of the dns level load balance
or works at the network level and why is
...important difference you can use traffic manager two-point-two your wordpress
svm as many as you want and it has a few other features that
...typical load...that just,
you know, sprays connections across a pool of resources doesn't have
...you can do things like round-robin you can wait things to a certain location you can actually wait things to a certain
location-based on the source ip address so...someone's coming in from europe or something you can
actually trigger them to go to a resources local in europe or asia
et cetera et cetera for the load balance or you can use that on the back in your my
sequel database to actually spread the load across multiple the
m running my sequel so let's sort of the difference...manager and load balance?
Now the other...I want to show you a switching gears a little bit here I want to show you the job how
...java here.
Just a couple okay all right so,
we've got some tools that we've created for the helping you deploy things on java
I'm going to clips now this is.
A tool that we actually built.
What it does it's a sample job application?
But, you can use.
And, basically the sample job application is a chat application looks like facebook or snatch
...something like that you...comments.
You can post pictures and video.
And, you can share.
It with your friendseverything expires after certain period of time
are all runs on a tomcat server on as your
and points to all the services that we have in a java st case we
have this java measure sdk which has a large services that connect to
blob table media service bus et-cetera,
et-cetera I've used all the services in this app if you're going to ignite by the way
if anyone's going night I'm going-to be showing that off a little more detail but this is an apt we built.
That just shows off basically every java sdk service that we have out there so in
a clips I've got the application here and
what I can do is I can actually create?
It's called as chat so I can actually create a new deployment project from this.
If I click a...project call anything I want.
In here I can choose the...ki want to use I can deploy
it from local I can also deploy it from a third-party jk
...on the web I can actually use a blob storage account to deploy the jk
say for the app server.
Use the tomcat.
See use tomcat eight today and it...which tomcat
amusing but those are all the different apple service sorry app
...that you have to use with your application.
You can actually deploy...third-party servers well you've got basically just on the
...you can...from custom download again the reason why
I wanted to play all these options is you can actually make the java package when you...smaller and,
we have some other settings you could use.
Here you can have the application we have session affinity
...remote debugging these are all documented...skip over these...the interest of time and,
basically once you've done with this you
can finish it and you can actually create worker roles.
Whoops.
...close.
...where's my project.
So, you can actually create multiple worker roles so in this case we got
role one because as the default
...great multiple worker roles with multiple sizes and when you want to deploy this to
asher it's automatically going to deploy all these things for you this runs on
...clips on top of...linux
and windows if you use windows you can test locally in emulation
mode before you actually deploy out to asher and once you deploy
...to agile just one-button so when you click this and I say published as
...cloud right there it's actually going to go ahead and publishes out to...cloud
...my subscription and let-me know when it's all done?
The one of the new features we have is actually generates and
...script how many people familiar and apache and.
...again so I won't go through the details but basically by the way this is ...
visual studio code running...xml is just a...xml based
a patching project allows you to repeatedly deploy things out to the
cloud or anywhere else it's basically a project manager a package
managers well for java and, one of the nice things about that is you
could take this and script and put it anywhere you want that and franz you don't have to have
a clips or plug-in running and it will do it from there.
...actually run and,
by the way visual studio code pretty good xml editor people talk about that but it's pretty cool it as
...syntax and...studies...
The intelligence to show you this real quick basically.
It's exactly the same thing so I...ways lot of time on that this is the jet
brain's intelligent product we also have similar plug-in for intelligentlyand,
...android studio which is based on...for those of
your interested in java development and deployment and all of the things I just
showed you are open-source on get...a and the
...open tech tools for intelligence here the windows
measure toolkit for eclipse with java is here as well and
the all hand-off are we who's speaking next.
Okay, thank you so,
I think we'll only eight minutes away...still have to scenarios
...I think...skip the last one which is the internet of things but,
we can part of the words ...I will...rest of time of for james to
talk about big data and the work we've done with imus some.
...this go back to powerpoint obvious...you up and...I'll be away.
And, I would lets you citron bring this time...that we're going to talk about big dot
a big data is an area that sort of the open-source communities absolutely
...isthere's many projects the sort of based around opensource that
target the processing of large-scale data...
generally distributed fashion so, the characteristics we say in some of these projects
...can be presented here and, the again another characteristic is that
...many components can fit into these various sizes of
...an into in project you can see a variety of offerings
they're both...sort of as...has developed many first potty services the
...fit into these prizes but at the same time there's many open-source
projects that can also fit into that and sometimes desirable the mix and match
...one first body services for data ingestion
...third-party or open-source projects to do some of the transformation all
processing on it so what we'd sort of trying to build-up the platform to provide
as much opportunity to do that as possible to give you the maximum flexibility also in
sort of big data to big...would you know,
there's many horizontal...of scenarios that ...and that I was
...drill into an oddity buy scenario but there's many more that sort of...in a some of them
...mostly horizontal some of the vertical but ...it's
not a one-size-fits-all so that's where the flexibility in the openness really comes into plot.
So, today I want to talk about a project we collaborated with a good friends at imis
electric they're the business of they're very large business but one of the projects that I
wanted to work on was about sort of instrumenting and gaining telemetry and
insights and monitoring of refineries large-scale generally remote
refineries sort of hashimoto armaments in which you
...sort of have all these computing work but they needed to do...and I want to
...leverage things like predictive analytics to determine five
years before hand they want to be able to look at historical
...society okay what's, you know, have the performance of this refunder been going...the last month
...water but, they also then needed to be able to have that
...dashboards as well so that authorizes sitting in the rooms in the refineries can
see how the process blows going what the quality levels a
lock and also see alerts getting fought off a valves filed
...go and take some action on that so they need that information as quickly as possible so they can go and
the disaster the system we worked out with the
...folks you can sort of see the system architecture diagram here it's a sort of fairly complex
but just basically...a sort of...ingestion point the...a...many instruments
out in the refinery that...sort of flowing their information out through a series of field guide
why's eventually it all funnels up into a tcp guy why that's sitting up in as
you they need some...reference data the flows across the
sort of metadata about that about that those instruments but as well as the
log telemetry itself so that sort of forks at that point you can see the instrument
...goes up into the top and gets process through...and storm and then sort of comes down
through occupies but also you can see often to the wrought where number five is listed
...we've got the ability to reach out into the edge...machine learning
service the...leveraging I sort of a operation laws
will published web service from a trying to model this model
is being continuously trying...as the data flows through but then I can do sort
of scoring of aggregated time series data to do that predictive analytics
...can see if...they can
...predictably determine where the qualities going to fall off and I can take corrective action on that
order about to hit some five years and take action before the fire actually because
and minimize costs on the refinery then the data obscene needs to flow...us to talk
about before about...sort of the ability to do stark analysis as well so
...a whole pile of reporting information that's needed so the data flows
out of the hd
in cyclist as an into sort of sort of stable
storage and we can leverage a bunch of reporting tools that show that information as well?
So, the one area do want to talk about you know,
as I mentioned before about the ability to mix and match...one of the one of the requirements the head
is that they needed to be able to run the system both on premise most of the refinery
customers sort of want to run...in the data center on in the refinery but then
they increasingly want to take advantage of cloud work in many...interested in moving
they workloads across the klout one just sort of reduce the infrastructure cost in the
refinery but to take some of the advantage of cloud-based machine learning cloud-based
reporting tools and sort of just generally sort of contemporary
upgrade the entire workload as msn wanted to be out of manage
this transition I sort of needed to achieve a certain degree of symmetry between what the on premise
the solution look like and what the cloud solution look like and
it's not sort of take a lowest common denominator so they want to be able to take advantage of some of
the cloud services that are available and still achieve essentially the same system so I
...at the way you see in this diagram and the sort of a large chunk of its
all contained within a do cluster so obviously the on premise they can run
...of the choice role...they run those standard
dupe components in a but they're sort of have to do all the management of
that either the operator on side or the msn sort of install
...and set that up capers running
capers manage so when I looked at the cloud solution I sub-set
...what's amal sort of automated manage why and I looked at the hd
inside service that up in measure which is just a management
...around the...project so it's there's...of super magic...just
apache the dupe through actually the horton works distribution of ...
but the provides management so if they m a filing the system automatically picks them up
...monitoring built-in a lot of the things happen automatically for...was a griped sort
of factor in the...that imis and considered the solution in that sort of hd
inside solution there are a bunch of things is i-device already installed
the storm already installed but for this particular solution what they
needed is that message ingestion service casco so categories the
opensource sub project of patchy the thatprovides
distributed messageingestion and message distribution and,
the actually inside service doesn't give the ability to run that today so that we sort of can work with them and said
okay well how do we into that existing hd and psych class the how do we get you
...that cactus service so we can run...diagram...the wind so...I just
...quickly show you what that look like if that one
...across perfect get rid of some apache stuff?
All right okay we're really running out of time sorry about that folks and,
can't even skip for this quickly whether the point I want to lead here is that
they is a custom script you we...right...some our...scripts
that downloaded the...binary is installed them on to the hd in
cyclist that customized them and we're able to go and run the
...topics connect them up to storm topology that
we're able to also manage and then the system ran through so
unfortunately I was going to psyche through all that but we're not going to do that now so, let's finish up
ashish I do apologize we...rather contents when I was
planning about thisfatherless plenty of time but anyway the
disrupt this up the scenario we didn't get a chance to show was
...pc foundation which a summarization bodied that very within several
...this them to allow them to interpret...between the entire the industrial
data but...that...way all the time thank you all for coming and the thanks to
all the grid speakers I have today and I hope you enjoy the rest of the peeled thank you?